Oh, my. Spring is here.
哎呀 春天到了呢
Is that Kitasan?
咦 北部
Kitasan, what are you doing here?
北部 你在做什么呢
Miss Nature…
优秀素质老师…
Again?
又来了吗
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
EPISODE 4: MY OWN LIGHT
(第4话 只属于我的光辉)
You lost?
跑不赢吗
Yes.
是的…
I lost in yesterday's Osaka Hai…
就是昨天的大阪杯…
I know I'm up against the best athletes
从这次开始都是高阶选手
but I challenged myself to win from the beginning to the end.
我本来抱着从第一战 就要赢到最后的想法去挑战
But…
但是…
I lost, by a tiny margin.
却以些微之差输掉了
Just a tiny margin? That's a bummer.
些微之差 那太可惜了
Exactly.
是啊 太可惜了
I was 3/4 length away from the first place in Arima Kinen too.
在有马纪念时也是输了 四分之三马身
I just ran out of fuel in the end…
都是因为我没能坚持到底…
Now that I think about it,
现在回想起来
I can't sprint as fast as Diamond on the final stretch,
我既没有光钻 那样俐落的尾段冲刺
nor do I have the burst Duramente does.
也没有像大鸣大放 那样豪迈的爆发力
It's bothering me
越是这样烦恼
and it makes me anxious.
心底就觉得越是不安…
Hey. Calm down first.
好…好了 你先冷静一点
We should get something sweet.
那个…像这种时候 我们就去吃点甜的吧
It's on me.
我请客哦
I'm sorry.
不好意思…
Don't worry about it.
没关系…
Just tell me what you want to eat.
今天你爱吃什么就尽量说
Miss Nature…
优秀素质老师…
Stop right there!
你们给我站住
You're not getting away today!
我今天绝对不会放过你们的
She's going berserk!
她发飙了
AIR GROOVE
(气槽)
MEJIRO PALMER, DAITAKU HELIOS
(目白善信 大德太阳)
Move aside!
等一下 快让开啊…
That was close…
吓死我了…
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
抱歉 没事吧
Are you hurt?
没有受伤吧
I'm fine.
我没事
I'm so glad to hear that.
是吗 太好了
Come with me now.
好了 走了
Are you sure you aren't injured?
你真的没事吗
Does it hurt somewhere?
没有哪里会痛吗
I have always had a sturdy physique.
我身体从以前就很强壮的
I never get sick or injured.
从来没有生病或受伤过
-A crab! -Whether it's hiking or swimming,
-是螃蟹耶 -不管是上山下海还是远足
-I caught one. -I don't get tired easily.
-我抓到了 -不管怎么玩都不会累
When I was in elementary school,
在小学时
-Relax. -I only got a few scratches
-不用怕哦 -就算从学校三楼跌下去
-Kita! -after I fell from the third floor.
-小北 -也只是一点擦伤而已
Kita!
小北
I'm very sure that I am not hurt at all.
总之我对自己的强健体格 很有自信的
Why?
你怎么了
Why don't you use your sturdy physique to your advantage?
你那强健的体格 不能应用到训练里吗
For example,
你看 比如说…
you can undergo an intensive training that's beyond everyone's endurance.
你可以接受其他人 无法承受的高强度训练
Maybe that will help you win more races.
要是训练有成的话不就能赢了吗
I'll ask the trainer about it.
那…那我去拜托训练师先生看看
No.
不行
You have a sturdy physique
就算你的身体比别人强壮
but you are not immune to physical injuries.
但有受伤风险这一点 依然没有改变
But…
但是…
But I want to be stronger.
我想要变强
Please put me under intensive training.
所以请让我做高强度训练
No.
还是不行
But Mr. Trainer…
训练师先生…
He's right. You can't compete when you're injured,
的确 要是因为受了伤而无法出赛
let alone win the race.
那就更别提想要获胜了
However,
不过…
you found a way to improve yourself and you want to give it a try.
找到了变强的方法 所以不想放弃
I know what you're going through now.
我也能理解这种心情
Teio, this is…
帝皇 可是…
Please say yes.
我也拜托你…
I appreciate that you're looking out for us, Mr. Trainer.
我很高兴训练师先生 可以如此认真地为我们着想
But
但是…
we run to win the race.
我们是为了获胜而参加比赛的
Suzuka, Teio…
铃鹿…帝皇…
I'm begging you, Mr. Trainer.
拜托你 训练师先生
-Mr. Trainer.
-训练师 -训练师先生
All right. I'll think about it.
我明白了 我思考一下
Thank you!
谢谢你
-Yay! -All the best.
-太好了 -要加油哦
Thanks.
好的 谢谢
-I'll talk to him. -Thanks.
-去找他商量一下吧 -好的 谢谢
-I'll do my best.
-我会加油的
I'll be your moral support.
我会帮你传送念力的
Your final sprint is getting better.
你的尾段冲刺越来越厉害了呢
I feel very motivated as Satsuki Sho inches closer.
一想到皋月赏要到了 心里就充满了干劲呢
Yeah.
是啊
I feel that way too.
我也是这种心情
Back then,
但我的那时的心情
I raced to break the G1 curse on our family.
是为了要打破里见的赛马娘 无法赢得GI的诅咒
Crown…
皇冠…
I have high hopes for you.
我很看好你哦
Please get the first G1 win for our family.
你要完成里见的夙愿 拿下第一个GI胜利
I will.
好
Kita, are you going out?
咦 小北你要出门吗
Yes, I start intensive training tomorrow.
是啊 明天开始要进行强化特训
For how long?
是哦 要去几天啊
"BRING NO MORE THAN 300 YEN OF SNACKS" Tenno Sho will begin in spring.
(只能带300圆的零食) 那个…天皇赏是春天开始
"BANANAS ARE NOT SNACKS"
(香蕉不包含在零食范围内)
"WAKE UP AT 5 AM EVERY DAY" So about a month, I think?
(早上5点要起床) 所以大概要去一个月…
I'm sorry, Diamond.
抱…抱歉 光钻
I won't be there for you in Satsuki Sho.
皋月赏时 我好像没办法去为你加油了
What do I do? What do I do?
怎…怎么办
Maybe I can take a day off?
那个… 可以在那个时候回来一下下吗
But I'll be in the mountains…
但那里是深山啊…
Don't worry. I'll win it.
没关系 我会赢的
I'll get first place.
我一定会赢得胜利的
Diamond…
光钻…
Let's work hard together, Kita.
所以小北也要加油哦
Yes.
好 我知道了
It's going to be so lonely
但是暂时要和光钻相隔两地了
when you're not with me.
好寂寞哦
Oh?
那是怎样
You know what?
这样的话…
Here.
给你
Your brooch?
胸针
Think of it as a piece of me.
你就把这个当成是我
All right?
好吗
Thank you, Diamond.
谢谢你 光钻
You're welcome. We'll work hard together.
不客气 我们各自加油吧
Sure.
好
You can have this horseshoe then.
那这个马蹄铁给你
It's so heavy.
很重呢
I can't eat any more…
我已经吃不下了…
Good morning.
早安
You two are early.
你们这么早就到啦
Mr. Trainer?
训练师先生
What… What is this?
那个我…这是怎么回事呢
Aren't you here for the intensive training?
你不是来参加强化特训的吗
So Bourbon is here to…
咦 那波旁是来…
She will be your special coach.
她是你这次的特别教练
"MIHONO BOURBON"
(美浦波旁)
Truth be told,
老实说 我并不熟悉高强度训练
I can't train you by making things up on the spot.
总不能用临阵磨枪的知识来训练你
I will show you no mercy
不管你怎么哭怎么求饶
no matter how hard you beg.
我既然答应了就绝对不会留情
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
Nice to meet you too.
也…也请你多多指教
Rice Shower will be in charge of your diet.
还有你的伙食 我请米浴来帮你安排
Hi, I'm Rice Shower.
我是米浴
I'll make delicious rice for you.
我会努力煮好吃的饭给你的
"RICE SHOWER"
(米浴)
You're in for a long haul.
接下来的每天都会很难熬
Stay strong, Kitasan.
但你要加油哦 北部
I will!
是 我会加油的
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
Four laps of sprinting on a muddy road.
山路冲刺 4趟
10 laps of sprinting with tires.
拖行巨大轮胎冲刺 10趟
10 laps of 1,000-meter interval running.
间歇跑步1000米 10趟
Break 100 bricks.
破砖 100块
10 rounds of climbing.
攀岩 10趟
Our goal
这次特训的目标
is to complete all those within three hours.
是在3小时内完成以上内容
Within three hours?
3小时内吗…
Is that even possible?
这真的办得到吗
You will spend twice the allotted time at the beginning.
一开始会花上两倍的时间吧
But theoretically, the tasks are feasible.
但理论上这并非不可能的任务
You can do it.
所以 你做得到
Get ready now.
那么 就位
It starts now?
已经开始了吗
Go!
开始
You have slowed down.
你的速度慢下来了
Yes.
是…
I thought it'd be like a training on a slope
我还以为跟斜坡跑步是一样的
but the road here is bumpy,
但是地面很不平整
with various degrees of inclination.
坡度也不一致 好难跑
It's more demanding for my leg muscles.
对腿部的负担完全不同
If I don't lower my centre of gravity, I can't proceed at all.
不压低重心用力的话 就完全无法前进
Use all your muscles.
要用上全身的肌肉
Yes…
是…
Form. Your form is wrong.
你的姿势偏掉了
Noted!
是
Here I go!
好
You need to focus.
你的意识不够集中
Yes…
是…
The next spot to grab…
接下来要抓住的地方…
That one?
是那里吗…
Maybe that spot is better.
但是这里好像比较好…
No, it's better to…
不对 比起这些…
Focus as you find the best gripping spot.
要一边集中精神一边寻找攀爬点
You'll need to be decisive.
要更快速地去判断状况
Yes…
是…
How long did I take?
时…时间是多少
Six hours.
6个小时
I expected that.
如我所料
You have a month
你还有一个月的时间
to shorten that to three hours.
一定要在这段时间里 在3个小时内完成训练内容
Okay…
是…
Let's eat now.
先来吃饭吧
Dinner's ready.
饭做好了哦
Dig in.
好了 趁热吃吧
Bon appétit.
我要开动了
You can ask for seconds if you're not full.
吃不够还能再盛哦
Thank you so much.
谢谢你
It's delicious!
好好吃哦
Rest your body in the hot spring later.
吃完饭后请去泡温泉 消除身体的疲劳
Hot spring?
温泉
Yay!
太好了
I'm fully rested now.
复活了
Ow…
好痛…
I have never felt this tired before.
这好像还是第一次这么累呢
If I survive this, I'll become stronger.
但要是撑过去的话 就一定能够变强的
I'll do my best tomorrow.
好 明天也要加油
MISO MACKEREL, GRILLED MACKEREL PIKE
(味噌青花鱼 蒲烧秋刀鱼)
YOU CAN DO IT
(加油)
You can achieve your time goal consistently now.
稳定达成目标时间了呢
Thank you.
谢谢你
Your weight is perfect. Your form is flawless.
体重完美维持 状态也万无一失
You're ready.
已经做好万全准备了
Winning the race is all that's left now.
是啊 再来就是赢下胜利
I will win it.
我一定会获胜的
My body is leaden.
总觉得身体好重…
Concentrate.
意识不够集中
Pace your breathing.
调整好呼吸
Yes.
是
Yes…
是…
This spot.
再来是这边…
And…
那个…
Goodnight.
那就晚安了
Rest well tonight.
好…要好好休息哦
Are you sure this is all right?
这样下去没问题吗
What are you referring to?
你的意思是…
She has made no progress lately.
这几天的时间几乎都没有缩短
"TENNO SHO AT MAY 1ST, LET'S GO!"
(加油 5月1日 天皇赏)
Her body is tired.
加上身体的疲劳
Her morale is low.
她的冲劲似乎也下降了
The real trial begins now.
现在才是关键
The true purpose of this training is to help her overcome this wall.
跨越这个难关 才是这次特训的真正目的
Master came up with this training regime for my comeback.
这原本是Master为了复出后的我 所想出来的训练方式
You mean Mr. Kuronuma?
黑沼先生吗
Your will is the key to winning a war of attrition.
要在拉锯战下胜出 靠的是"精神力"
In other words, you have to have
也就是在极限状态下
an unyielding determination to win under extreme duress.
依然能为了胜利 顽强抵抗的强烈意志
It's up to her now
但能不能领悟到这一点
whether she can find this level of resolution or not.
就要看她接下的表现
I let Master down.
我没能回应Master对我的期待
So I hope Kitasan,
所以
who reminds me of myself, can overcome this wall.
我才希望跟我很相像的她 可以跨越这个难关
I don't think I can do it.
我可能不行了…
No, I can't give up here.
不行…不可以气馁
Diamond would have aced this in seconds.
如果是光钻的话 一定马上就能完成了吧
Diamond…
光钻…
Eh?
咦
Tomorrow is…
难道明天就是…
Let me see.
我看看
Kitasan, the bread is ready.
北部…面包烤好…了
Bourbon!
波旁…
What's the matter?
怎么了
I found this in Kitasan's tent.
我…我在北部的帐篷里找到这个…
I WILL REGAIN MY MOTIVATION
(我去找回冲劲)
180KM TO NAKAYAMA RACECOURSE
(距离中山竞马赛还有180公里)
G1 SATSUKI SHO
(GI 皋月赏)
After the last bend,
过了最后弯道
Satono Diamond makes an appearance.
里见光钻来了
Super Mate is there too.
默契之交也冲上来了
Diamond!
光钻
A 310-meter-long stretch
长达310米直线
is the distance between them and their dreams.
是连接梦想的直线
Lawnmower is in the lead.
领先再前的是割草者
Diamond is coming up on the flank.
从外侧数来是里见光钻
Jewel Spinel…
珠宝尖晶…
Satono Diamond charges in from the flank.
外侧的里见光钻冲上来了
Satono Diamond!
里见光钻冲上来了
Diamond!
光钻
Lawnmower is still in the lead.
领先的一样是割草者
Behind her are Jewel Spinel and Super Mate.
再来是珠宝尖晶 那默契之交呢
Diamond!
光钻
Divinity accelerates!
居然 神力从外侧冲出来了
Divinity puts everyone behind her.
神力从外侧一口气甩开众人
Super Mate follows suit.
默契之交也接着跟了上去
Divinity!
神力
What a formidable sprint!
好可怕的尾段冲刺
And she won't stop.
继续不断地往前冲
Divinity touches the finishing line!
神力冲过终点
She overtook all her opponents in one swoop!
一口气解决了所有人
Her speed is unmatched.
神力的主角地位不容动摇
1 minute 57.9 seconds is her time.
完赛时间 1分57秒9
It's the best record in this course!
是最佳场地记录
"DELIBERATING"
(审议)
CONFIRMED
(确定)
She was in a great form.
她明明状况不错的
She failed to break her family's curse.
果然还是无法打破里见的诅咒吗
Diamond…
光钻…
I will win.
我一定会赢得胜利的
I hope she's okay…
她没事吧…
Do you agree with the scoreboard?
对于审议的结果 您有什么想法呢
I accept the outcome.
我接受这个结果
If I'm faster, the outcome will be different.
要是我实力坚强 自然能推翻这种结果
This just shows that my determination to win isn't strong enough.
是我的实力… 对胜利的执着还不够强烈
Some of the audience said that you were cursed. Do you agree with them?
观众席也有传出 这是否为里见的诅咒所致的结果
My performance in the Japanese Derby will prove them wrong.
请看着我在日本德比的表现吧
My name is Satono Diamond.
我的名字是里见光钻
A diamond shines wherever it goes.
钻石是绽放无上光芒的至宝
And it doesn't break easily, regardless of the hardship.
无论遇到何种困难都不会破碎
The bread is ready.
面包烤好了哦
It seems like you regained your motivation.
看来你找回冲劲了
Yes.
是
Let's continue, shall we?
那我们就继续吧
The real thing begins now.
现在才开始 现在才正要开始呢
My body might feel heavy.
就算身体再怎么沉重
It might be difficult to lift my legs.
就算完全无法前进
But I won't admit defeat.
我也不会感到挫折
I will forge on in the face of adversity.
无论有多痛苦 我都要向前迈进
Come what may,
无论是什么困难
I'll crush it.
我都要去粉碎它
Next time, I will…
下一次 我一定要…
10 seconds left.
还有10秒
I will secure it in my hands.
一定要牢牢抓住
Victory will be mine!
我要赢得胜利
You overcame the wall.
跨越那道高墙了呢
Let's win Tenno Sho this spring.
我们去赢下春季天皇赏吧
Yes!
是